and today we are going to talk about how
to scale our applications to millions of
users this video is based on a talk that
AWS gives every year where expert
Architects share advice and architecture
tips to build applications that can
scale to the max using the latest Cloud
Technologies we are going to start by
taking a look at the simplest
architecture we can think of and see how
we can improve it step by step until it
can handle millions of users and
requests per second this architecture is
what we used to do in the old days the
user is hitting Route 53 AWS DNS service
and the request is being forwarded to a
single server that does it all one
single server is serving the front end
running the logic of the backend and
hosting this database even though this
might work we are doing something we
should not do putting all the eggs in
one basket when we put all the eggs in
one basket when a server does everything
and the server goes down everything goes
down with it front-end backend and
database thanks to new front-end
Frameworks we have started to separate
front-end from backend and using AWS and
that separation will look like this
where we are using one server optimized
for static files serving our front-end
and a back-end hosting our logic and
data for our backend server we have many
options Amazon ec2 for virtual servers
Amazon ECS eks or fargate for container
management or AWS Lambda for a stateless
code execution at scale if we choose ec2
which is a single server we can go very
far but we don't have failover or
redundancy servers and we are still
putting all X in one basket if we look
at the options we have for compute there
is a spectrum the lower we go the more
we have to do configure and be
responsible for which is the case if we
choose to go to ec2 but if we go
serverless as you can see the only thing
we have to worry about is our code and
this is why Amazon recommends AWS app
Runner which is a good balance between
not having to worry about configuration
but also being in control of your
architecture with AWS app Runner we get
a load of balancer a server will Auto
scaling and other things that make
deploying elastic apps super easy using
App Runner it is now easier to scale and
increase performance for us as
developers the application became easier
to deploy and the eggs are not all in
one basket but what about the database
should we go for SQL or no SQL according
to AWS we should start with SQL
databases SQL is an established and
well-known technology there are lots of
existing code communities books and you
are not going to break SQL databases
with your first million users but if
you're one of those special cases that
might have terabytes of data per year
then you may need no SQL you might also
need nosql if you're building super low
latency applications have metadata
driven data sets or have an app that
ingests data at Super speeds like
thousands of Records per second because
that is not most of us we're going to go
with SQL the question is which SQL
database should we use Amazon Aurora is
the fastest growing service in the
history of AWS it is a serverless SQL
database that scales on demand it's
pay-per-use and according to Amazon is
several times faster than the standard
MySQL and postgresql database it's fully
managed which means that we don't have
to worry about Hardware provisioning
software patching setup configuration or
backups combining it all we will end up
with an architecture that has Auto
scaling both in the server using App
Runner and the database using Aurora we
don't manage the infrastructure which
means we don't have to worry about
updates operative systems security and
all that with this architecture we can
go incredibly far we can scale to more
than 10 000 users easy but here is where
Maybe we are going to have to optimize
some of the slow parts we can optimize
front-end backend and database in
different ways depending on what the
slow parts are to optimize the front end
we can use Amazon cloudfront a CDN or
content delivery Network that will copy
our static front-end file into more than
410 locations globally and give the
files to our users from the servers
closer to them to optimize the database
we can use Amazon RDS proxy with Aurora
read replicas read replicas are
read-only databases that get updated
only by the main database if we have
lots of read requests we can offload
some of the work of the main database by
using RDS proxy to redirect the read
request to the read replica and forward
the right request to the main one the
great thing about this pattern is that
you can keep adding more and more
replicas as you need them another thing
that we can do to make our database
faster is to not use the database at all
using Amazon elastic cache we can cache
the database responses to the most
expensive queries of our application in
this way when those requests come in we
can just provide the cached results from
elastic cache instead of hitting in the
database and now it's time to optimize
the bucket if we look at how app Runner
looks like under the hood we will see
that it is a load balancer and I request
a router that will hit ECS far gate
tasks where our backing code is running
the good news is that we can just scale
the number of ECS fargate tasks as
needed using App Runner with more
instances and basic configuration we can
scale to 5 000 concurrent requests which
at 2 seconds per request will mean that
you can perform more than 150
000 requests per minute this
architecture can handle hundreds of
thousands of requests and can take you
to millions of users but this is where
where you might start hitting some
limits of the services you are using
since we have a bunch of database
replicas for read operations we are okay
on that side but maybe because we only
have one database for write operations
that database might start to tap out
uprunner today has a limit of 200
connections per instance and we can only
have 25 instances per application if you
need more than that here is where you
might have to start rethinking the
architecture of your application and
start thinking about moving to a micro
service architecture the first thing we
could do to sort of divide our
application into multiple pieces is to
Federate our database we can divide our
big monolithic database into small
clusters that we can scale as we saw
before by adding read replicas and using
elastic cache whenever we need it maybe
if you have lots of data and it's coming
too quickly and is not structured it's
time to start shifting to no SQL you can
use dynamodb capable of millions of
transactions per second and used heavily
by big companies like amazon.com to
optimize the backend even more you can
take apart some of the routes of your
API and Leverage The Power of Lambda
functions to run your code just like we
divided our database we can divide our
API in small parts and we can use Amazon
API Gateway as the conductor redirecting
requests to different parts of our
application and it is with this idea of
separating caching and scaling the slow
part of our application that we can hit
10 million users to set yourself up for
Success the way you architect your
application is a decision that should be
made with careful consideration from the
start which is why AWS is sponsoring
this video AWS invites you to join the
AWS Builders online series The AWS
Builders online series is a free virtual
event designed to equip you with
essential AWS knowledge and
Architectural best practices it will
take place on Thursday July 13 of 2023.
regardless of whether you are a newbie
or an advanced user there is something
for everyone to learn the event will
feature free online training from AWS
experts for beginners covering the
basics of the AWS cloud and how to get
the most out of it in just three hours
and there will be 12 sessions of free
online training from AWS experts
covering cost optimization container
services compute Services databases data
pipelines and successful case studies
for more details on configuring Cloud
architectures for 10 million users check
out the opening session of the event
there will be technical demos and
attendees can even receive a certificate
of participation it's completely free
all you need to do is register by
clicking the link below in just three
hours you will go from learning the
concepts of AWS Cloud Core services to
actually utilizing the AWS Cloud don't
miss this free online event
see you on the next one bye bye